Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986/ | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Education in full-stack development from UCLA, with contributions on multiple collaborations. Experienced independent researcher and problem solver. Values community, ethics, integrity, and business sense, having spent years as a business manager and scientist. Extensive teaching experience lends itself to public speaking, leadership, and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously pursuing self-improvement.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages. Python as secondary language, with ability and skill to learn further languages.
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js)
- Use of established libraries such as Redux, jQuery, Flask, Sass, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Material UI, TypeScript, Jinja
- SQL database work, through MySQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, and Sequelize
- Non-relational database management through MongoDB and mongoose, as well as Firebase
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, mobileresponsive web design, and familiarity with code testing using tools such as Postman and Jest
- AJAX calls for integrating APIs for example, Facebook, Twitter, and Google Cloud APIs
- Skill in researching programming languages and techniques for example, Python, basic PHP, and basic C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

SAMPLE PROJECTS

• Full portfolio located at https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Color Rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler-github | https://bit.ly/color-rippler

- Code that renders up to thousands of interactive components in the DOM, using React
- Combines front-end design with JavaScript algorithms. MERN stack is used for data storage, user authentication, and back-end routing.

Express Bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender-github | https://bit.ly/express-bartender

- Executed lead back-end scripting for a small team of coders. Led back-end database and routing design. Programmed storage and updates of user information with SQL database.
- Helped teammates solve code difficulties, reviewed team code on GitHub, and contributed to frontend and overall website design.
- Programmed SQL database of drink recipes acquired through AJAX calls to APIs.

EMPLOYMENT

Aim-Hi Global, LLC. | https://aimhiglobal.com

December 2020 - Current

- Web Development Intern
- Implemented new app user settings features, added protected route functionality, refactored code, and fixed various bugs while working with React and Firebase
- Collaborated on ongoing programming of interaction with big data social media APIs, such as Facebook and Twitter, as well as the subsequent organization and graphing of retrieved data

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Current

- Worked independently on small Python timesheet and balance sheet software programs, streamlining company workflow
- Rigorous documentation and coordination of construction projects, with spending in the hundreds of thousands, benefited both tenants and the company through substantial property improvement
- Contributed to business decision making, such as management of over a dozen buildings, and purchasing decisions for properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, as well as two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

CS50 Web Programming Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online CS50 Computer Science Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine

In Progress